A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Office of the Arts, Program Files FA640
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grantee Media Files, 1965-1979; XVI
  - Abstraction -- Roemer-Young Associates, 1971; Sound, Color, 9 minutes. (Reel AV 1957, Reel AV 2004)
    See also: Ford Foundation grant 06600421 (PA66-421), The American Federation Of Arts, Inc., DEVELOP SIXTEEN ART INSTRUCTION FILMS AND RELATED INSTRUCTIONAL MATERIALS FOR USE IN THE FIFTH GRADE.
  - Shape -- Roemer-Young Associates, 1971; Film, Silent, Color, 13 minutes. (Reel AV 1899, Reel AV 2001, Reel AV 1895, Reel AV 2002)
    Seemingly stock footage of shapes found nature, architecture, human activity, and fine art: silhouettes of buildings and bridges, shadows of humans at play, natural forms like branches and flowers, and depictions of shape in paintings and sculptures. From Roemer, Young and Associates.
    Separated to Ford Foundation Film collection
  - Movement -- Roemer-Young Associates, 1971; Film, Silent, Color, 12 minutes. (Reel AV 1874, Reel AV 1896, Reel AV 2003)
    Seemingly stock footage of motion and movement in nature, architecture, technology, and fine art: leaves in the wind, rushing water, children running and playing, machines in factories, and depictions of movement in paintings and sculptures. From Roemer, Young and Associates.
  - Light -- Roemer-Young Associates, 1971; Film, Sound, Color, 9 minutes. (Reel AV 2005, Reel AV 1996)
    Art film about light and its influence in different environments. Photographed and direct by Manfred Kirchheimer., and produced by Roemer-Young Associates.
  - Return of the Reluctant Prodigy -- International Piano Archives, 1977-1979; Film, Sound, Color, 34 minutes.; Film (Reel AV 1995)
    Other Finding Aids
    See Ford Foundation film AV 1995 here:
    FA466 Film collection - AV 1995
    Documentary on Hungarian born American pianist Ervin Nyiregyhazi recording music for the International Piano Archive funded by a Ford Foundation grant. Copyright CTV Television Network 1978 Ltd.
    See also: Ford Foundation grant 07800001 (PA78-1), International Piano Archives, TO RECORD PIANIST OF GREAT HISTORICAL AND MUSICAL IMPORTANCE, and Ford Foundation grant 07850537 (PA785-537), International Piano Archives, FOR EXPENSES RELATED TO RECORDING THE PLAYING OF THE PIANIST, ERVIN NYIREGYHAZI.
  - Opus One, number 8, side one, 1970 March 24 (Box 72, Reel AV 6299)
    2012:078:015
    See also: Ford Foundation grant 06990584 (PA699-584), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), DEMON. OF NEW WAYS TO DISSEMINATE CONTEMPORARY AMERICAN MUSIC THROUGH COORDINATED RELEASES IN PUBLISHED AND RECORDED EDITIONS.
  - Opus One, number 8, side two, 1970 March 24 (Box 72, Reel AV 6300)
    2012:078:016
  - Nyiregyhazi -- International Piano Archives, 1977-1979; Film, Sound, Color, 22 minutes; Film (Reel AV 1993)
    See Ford Foundation film AV 1993 here:
    FA466 Film collection - AV 1993
    Documentary on Hungarian born American pianist Ervin Nyiregyhazi recording music for the International Piano Archive funded by a Ford Foundation grant.
    See also: Ford Foundation grant 07800001 (PA78-1), International Piano Archives, TO RECORD PIANIST OF GREAT HISTORICAL AND MUSICAL IMPORTANCE.
  - Nikos Skalkottas -- Eight variations on a Greek folk tune for piano trio, Record (Box 68, Disk AV 5341)
    2012:078:017
    See also: Ford Foundation grant 06800617 (PA68-617), Society Of The Friends Of N. Skalkottas, COMPLETION OF THE EDITING FOR PUBLICATION OF THE WORKS OF NIKOS SKALKOTTAS.
  - Musical Atlas -- International Institute of Comparative Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5342)
    2012:078:018
    See also: Ford Foundation grant 07000348 (PA70-348), International Institute of Comparative Music, GENERAL SUPPORT.
  - New Orleans Philharmonic Orchestra, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5343)
    2012:078:019
    See also: Ford Foundation grant 06600303 (PA66-303), The New Orleans Philharmonic Symphony Society, DEVELOPMENT AND CONSOLIDATION OF AMERICAN SYMPHONY ORCHESTRAS (GENERAL SUPPORT).
  - International Contemporary Music Exchange -- Outstanding Contemporary Orchestral Compositions of the United States, Nov 25, 1975 (Box 68, Disk AV 5344)
    2012:078:020
    See also: Ford Foundation grant 07300556 (PA73-556), The International Contemporary Music Exchange, Inc., PARTIAL SUPPORT FOR THE ESTABLISHMENT OF THE INTERNATIONAL CONTEMPORARY MUSIC EXCHANGES AMERICAN BRANCH & INT'L HEADQUARTERS.
  - Jani Christou -- Late Works -- Greek Association for Contemporary Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5345)
    2012:078:021
    See also: Ford Foundation grant 06800614 (PA68-614), Greek Association of Contemporary Music, SUPPORT FOR THE ACTIVITIES OF THE HELLENIC ASSOCIATION FOR CONTEMPORARY MUSIC.
  - Songs of Kasos and Karpathos -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5346)
    2012:078:022
    See also: Ford Foundation grant 07800083 (PA72-83): Society For The Dissemination Of Greek Music, RECORDING, PRODUCTION AND DISTRIBUTION OF RECORDS OF GREEK FOLK AND ECCLESIASTICAL MUSIC.
  - Songs of Rhodes, Chalki and Symi -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5347)
    2012:078:023
  - Songs of Amorgos, Kythnos and Sifnos -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5348)
    2012:078:024
  - Songs of Roumeli -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5349)
    2012:078:025
  - Songs of Mytilene and Chios -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5350)
    2012:078:026
  - Songs of Epirus -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5351)
    2012:078:027
  - Byzantine Hymns of the Epitaphios and Easter -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5352)
    2012:078:028
  - Songs of the Peleponnesos -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5353)
    2012:078:029
  - Songs of Crete -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated; Record (Box 68, Disk AV 5354)
    RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply.
    2012:078:030
  - Songs of the Ionian Islands -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5355)
    2012:078:031
  - Hymns and Laments for the Fall of Constantinople -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5356)
    2012:078:032
  - Songs of Eastern Macedonia -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5357)
    2012:078:033
  - Songs of Constantinople and the Sea of Marmara -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5358)
    2012:078:034
  - Songs of Western Macedonia -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5359)
    2012:078:035
  - Songs of Thrace -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated; 2 copies. (Box 68, Disk AV 5360)
    2012:078:036
  - The Service of the Akathistos Hymn -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5361)
    2012:078:037
  - Songs of Thasos, Lemnos and Samothrace -- Society for the Dissemination of Greek Music, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5362)
    2012:078:038
  - Greek Composers, from the 3rd Hellenic Week of Contemporary Music -- Greek Association of Contemporary Music, 1968 (Box 68, Disk AV 5365)
    2012:078:043
  - 18 Concert Studies, The Unaccompanied Clarinet, by Nathan Ivan Kaplan -- Grenadilla Society, 1975 (Box 68, Disk AV 5366)
    2012:078:044
  - Brahms Trio for Clarinet, Violoncello and Piano -- Grenadilla Society, undated (Box 68, Disk AV 5367)
    2012:078:045
  - Nyiregyhazi (Tchaikovsky, Bortkiewicz, Grieg, Blanchet) -- International Piano Archives, 1979 (Box 68, Disk AV 5368)
    2012:078:046
  - Nyiregyhazi -- All Liszt Program -- International Piano Archives, 1978 (Box 68, Disk AV 5369)
    2012:078:047
  - Nyiregyhazi -- International Piano Archives (Box 69, Disk AV 5370)
    2012:078:048
  - Aaron Copland -- Complete Music for Solo Piano -- International Contemporary Music Exchange, undated; Record (Box 69, Disk AV 5372)
    2012:078:050
    See also: Ford Foundation grant 07850221 (PA785-221), The International Contemporary Music Exchange, Inc., FACILITATE RECORDINGS OF PIANO MUSIC BY COMPOSER AARON COPLAND.
  - 1, 2, and 4th Hellenic Week of Contemporary Music (2nd Series) -- Greek Association for Contemporary Music (Box 69, Disk AV 5382)
    2012:078:060
  - UNESCO Collection -- Musical Sources -- Bali: Court Music and Banjar Music -- International Institute of Comparative Music (Box 69, Disk AV 5374)
    2012:078:052
  - UNESCO Collection -- Musical Sources – Tibetan Ritual -- International Institute of Comparative Music (Box 69, Disk AV 5373)
    2012:078:051
  - UNESCO Collection -- Musical Sources – Judische Musik -- International Institute of Comparative Music (Box 69, Disk AV 5380)
    2012:078:058
  - UNESCO Collection -- Musical Sources -- North India, Vocal Music, Dhrupad and Khyal -- International Institute of Comparative Music (Box 69, Disk AV 5379)
    2012:078:057
  - UNESCO Collection -- Musical Sources -- Arabian Music: Maqam -- International Institute of Comparative Music (Box 69, Disk AV 5378)
    2012:078:078:056
  - UNESCO Collection -- Musical Sources -- Iranian Dastgah -- International Institute of Comparative Music (Box 69, Disk AV 5377)
    2012:078:055
  - UNESCO Collection -- Musical Sources -- Royal Music of Cambodia -- International Institute of Comparative Music (Box 69, Disk AV 5376)
    2012:078:054
  - UNESCO Collection -- Musical Sources -- Java, Historische Gamelan -Orchester-- International Institute of Comparative Music (Box 69, Disk AV 5375)
    2012:078:053
  - Musical Atlas: Bali -- International Institute of Comparative Music, undated (Box 69, Disk AV 5371)
    2012:078:049
  - Musical Atlas: Bengal -- International Institute of Comparative Music (Box 68, Disk AV 5363)
    2012:078:039
  - Musical Atlas: Cambodia -- International Institute of Comparative Music (Box 68, Disk AV 5364)
    2012:078:040
  - Musical Atlas: Syria -- International Institute of Comparative Music (Box 69, Disk AV 5381)
    2012:078:059
- Appendix A: Reports, 1956-1972
  - Armsey, James W.; Strengthening Communications for Public Enlightenment, May 26, 1959 (Report #019972)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; Finland -- The Situation of the Theatre, Music, Cinema and the Plastic Arts, Nov 1970 (Report #019957)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; Music in the Netherlands (Report #019954)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; The Music Situation in Great Britain, 1968 (Report #019959)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; The Music Situation in Italy, 1966 (Report #019951)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; Norway -- The Situation of the Plastic Arts, Theatre, Music, Literature Cinema, Jul 1970 (Report #019955)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; The Official School of Cinematography in Spain, Mar 1969 (Report #019963)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; The Situation of Music in Spain, Feb 1969 (Report #019964)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; The Situation of Music, the Theater and the Plastic Arts in Portugal, May 1968 (Report #019950)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; The Situation of the Plastic Arts in Spain, May 1969 (Report #019953)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; The Situation of the Theatre, Music, Cinema, and the Plastic Arts in Denmark, Apr 1970 (Report #019958)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; The Situation of the Theatre in Great Britain, 1969 (Report #019960)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; Situation of the Theater and Music in Switzerland, 1969 (Report #019961)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; The Situation of the Theater in Spain, Mar 1969 (Report #019962)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; Sweden -- The Situation of the Theatre, Music, Plastic Arts, Novelist, Cinema, 1970 (Report #019956)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby; The Theater in the Federal Republic of Germany, Dec 1967 (Report #019952)
  - Ford Foundation; The Ford Foundation Board of Trustees Meeting -- September 28-29, 1956, Nov 21, 1956 (Report #019976)
    Report 019976 is unavailable.
  - Ford Foundation; National Council of the Arts -- Program Paper and Board of Trustees Draft Resolution (Report #019968)
  - Lerner, J.B.; The Performing Arts Survey System, May 24, 1972 (Report #019965)
  - McPeak, William; A Proposal for a Program in the Arts of National Scope, Jan 4, 1960 (Report #019975)
    Report 019975 is unavailable.
  - Neilsen, Waldemar A.; International Scientific, Educational and Cultural Exchange, May 27, 1959 (Report #019973)
  - Zeigler, Joseph Wesley; Options for Opportunity Resources for the Arts, May 31, 1979 (Report #019971)
  - Economic and Social Positions of the Artists and His Institutions, Apr 8, 1958 (Report #019970)
  - Humanistic Scholarship -- Conference of Humanities, 1958 (Report #019974)